Alessandro **Pezzato**

Trebaseleghe, PD, Italy

💌 alessandro@pezzato.net | 👑 1986 | 😭 alepez.dev | 🖸 alepez | 😽 alepez | 🗟 alessandro-pezzato | 🛅 alessandropezzato

"Learn. Code. Teach. Repeat."

Summary.

With over 18 years of professional software development experience and a passion for programming that began at the age of 11, I bring a wealth of expertise to the table.

Specializing in C++ since 2007, I have consistently delivered high-quality solutions throughout my career.

I offer consulting, training, and software development services to companies, specializing in C, C++, Rust, Linux, and technologies for embedded and IoT systems.

Since 2014, I have been working as an independent software developer, taking on various projects.

In addition to my development work, I have also taken on the role of a trainer, sharing my knowledge and expertise with other developers to help them enhance their skills.

I have organized and conducted numerous C++ and Rust courses, providing comprehensive training on best practices and various software development methodologies.

As both a developer and a trainer, I am committed to staying up-to-date with the latest industry trends and technologies, ensuring that I can provide the most relevant and valuable guidance to my clients and students.

Work Experience (as independent consultant) _____

Bluewind S.r.l.

DEVELOPER, CONSULTANT, TRAINER

- Implemented drivers and firmware for various safety critical embedded systems for automotive, marine and and industrial products. Languages: C. C++. Rust.
- Organized C++ and Rust courses for about ten developers.

Texa S.p.A. Monastier, Italy

DEVELOPER, CONSULTANT, TRAINER

2014 - Present

- Developed C++ communication libraries (both embedded and server side) for an IoT automotive project to handle real-time remote diagnostic data of about 500 thousands vehicles.
- Organized multiple C++ courses between 2015 and 2022, a total of about 150 hours and 40 developers.

Spring Tech Innovations S.r.l.

Limena, Italy

DEVELOPER, CONSULTANT

2022

• Developed C++ software for an home automation and alarm system.

Ferrous Systems GmbH

Berlin, Germany

• Developed Rust compiler tests for Ferrocene qualified toolchain.

MERMEC S.p.A.

DEVELOPER, CONSULTANT

Morgano, Italy

DEVELOPER, CONSULTANT

2020 - 2022

• Developed C++ and C# software for surface inspection of steel products.

ASTRA Yacht S.r.l.

Monfalcone, Italy 2015 - 2022

• Developed C++ software for sailboat real-time performance analysis.

Qascom S.r.l.

TRAINER

TRAINER

Bassano del Grappa, Italy

• Organized a 45 hours C++ course for 20 developers working on GNSS and space cybersecurity systems.

2021

Salvagnini S.p.A.

Sarego, Italy 2019 - 2020

• Organized a course on modern C++ and Test Driven Development, for a total of 24 hours and 10 developers.

• Organized a course on Test Driven Development for C and C++, for a total of 24 hours and 10 developers.

Ubilot S.r.l.Bassano del Grappa, Italy

2019

2014 - 2018)

DEVELOPER, CONSULTANT

• Developed C++ and C# software.

Adatta S.r.l. Padova, Italy

Trainer 20

Coached a junior C++ developer.

Carel S.p.A. Brugine, Italy

Developer, Consultant

Developed C++ software and C Linux drivers for HVAC products.

GM Trading srls

Borgoricco, Italy

Developer 2014 - 2018

· Developed (JavaScript) UI of an e-commerce website

Work Experience (employee)

Vimage S.r.l. Mirano, Italy

Lead Software Developer Jul 2007 - Jul 2014

- Coordinated and mentored the R&D team of up to 5 developers.
- Worked on different projects for museums, stores and events. Most projects involved interactive projections, touchscreens, touchless sensors
 and computer vision.
- Developed company's core C++ libraries for 2d and 3d games.
- Developed a company Linux distribution based on Gentoo Linux.

Nasch S.r.l. Padova, Italy

 Web Developer
 Oct 2005 - Apr 2007

- Developed local companies websites (PHP and JavaScript).
- Developed a web tv platform (Flash and ActionScript 3)

Education

Liceo Scientifico E. Majorana Mirano, Italy

SCIENTIFIC HIGH SCHOOL DIPLOMA WITH A SPECIALIZATION IN THE NATIONAL INFORMATICS PLAN (P.N.I.) 2001 - 2005

Università di Padova Padua, Italy

MECHANICAL ENGINEERING (INCOMPLETE) 2005 - 2006

Università Ca' Foscari Venezia

Venice, Italy

Business Administration (Incomplete) 2006 - 2008

Skills_

Programming tools and techniques Git, gdb, Docker, NeoVim, CLion, TDD

Programming Languages C++, C, Rust, JavaScript, Python, Haskell, C#, Bash

Languages Italian, English

Non-profit _____

 CodingGym
 www.coding-gym.org

Trainer Feb. 2018 - Present

- Organizer of local (Padova and Castelfranco Veneto) programming lab
- As a trainer, I have designed exercises that cover algorithms, data structures, and problem-solving for the monthly programming workshop.
- · As a trainer, I have conducted monthly free programming workshops, assisting over 100 participants throughout the years.

I hereby authorize the use of my personal data in accordance to the GDPR 679/16 - European regulation on the protection of personal data.

AUGUST 30, 2023 ALESSANDRO PEZZATO · RÉSUMÉ 2